# Yuanyuan Hu

A passionate **user experience designer** and **team player** who brings technologies from the lab to everyday life to build a desirable future for all.

Tel: (312)709-9034 Email: yhu76@id.iit.edu Location: Chicago, IL

Design Portfolio: yuanyuanhu96.github.io linkedin.com/in/yuanyuan-hu-design

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX Design Intern, Narrative Science | 08/2020 - Present | Chicago, IL |

Designing the onboarding experience of Lexio - a B2B data storytelling product.

- o Developing the journey map, concepts, and interaction designs to increase adoption;
- o Synthesizing user research and facilitating discussions to inform the roadmap.

Research & Design Intern, Nokia | 06/2020 - 08/2020 | Naperville, IL |

Led the research and created a new SaaS concept for future portfolio consideration.

- o Initiated user research and competitive analysis to find product opportunities;
- o Facilitated design in an interdisciplinary team to develop a new product concept;
- o This concept was recognized by senior executives and moved for further validation.

UX Design Intern, Nokia | 06/2019 - 08/2019 | Naperville, IL |

Designed the system to support the digital transformation of service providers.

- o Co-created ideas with executives, and developed three distinct product concepts;
- o Designed user flows, information architecture, and UI, presented with user journeys;
- o These concepts have evolved into a key product of Nokia Software.

Product Manager, Yofish Fintech | 03/2018 - 08/2018 | Shanghai |

Built a new version of the lottery purchasing APP for the younger generations.

- o Prioritized requirements from the business, user, and technology perspectives;
- o Designed information architectures and interactions, leveraging reusable modules;
- o Iterated product requirement documents and coordinated design and development.

Research Assistant, Tongji University | 07/2017 - 03/2018 | Shanghai |

Intel - research on human-robot interaction and smart interaction

- o Designed and conducted field trials for new robotic technologies;
- Researched interaction design for adaptive learning robotic systems.

Huawei - user intention prediction model for proactive human-machine interface

- o Categorized scenarios and functions by the content needs and design patterns;
- Developed interaction frameworks and prediction models with computer scientists;
- o Suggested use cases, highlighting data-gathering approaches.

# **PROJECTS**

UX Designer, Fidelity Investments Project | 01/2020 - 05/2020 | Chicago, IL |

Designed a platform to facilitate interactions between Fidelity and gig-economy workers.

- o Identified job to be done of gig workers and the value that Fidelity could provide;
- o Created an end to end experience for Fidelity to meet customers in their needs.

Service Designer, City Clerk Chicago Project | 08/2019 - 12/2019 | Chicago, IL |

Designed a service that enables residents to take initiatives in non-moving violations.

- o Understood stakeholders' needs; identified trust and communication issues;
- Proposed a fairer post-violation solution illustrated by prototypes and a service blueprint;
- o Honored by Fast Company's 2020 Innovation by Design Awards.

# **EDUCATION**

Illinois Institute of Technology

Master of Design,

**Human-Computer Interaction** 

GPA: 3.86

08/2018 - 12/2020

**Tongji University** 

Bachelor of Engineering, Industrial Design

09/2014 - 07/2018

#### **SKILLS**

## **User-centered Design**

Design Thinking
Stakeholder Interview
Heuristic Evaluation
Usability Test
Workshop Facilitation

### **Interaction Design**

User Flow
Information Architecture
Wireframe
UI Design
Sketch & InVision & Principle
Figma & Adobe XD

# **Other Skills**

HTML & CSS & JavaScript Adobe Premiere Pro Adobe Illustrator Data Visualization

## **AWARDS**

Fast Company's 2020 Innovation by Design Awards Students Category Finalist

China-US Young Maker Competition (2017) Second Prize

Design Shanghai Exhibition (2016) Outstanding Participants